Dayton, Ohio. St. Luke's United Church of Christ records, 1908-2013.
Congregational Library & Archives
Dayton, Ohio. St. Luke's United Church of Christ records, 1908-2013.
RG5331
Congregational Library & Archives
.98 Cubic Feet
(3 boxes)
In 1908, a group of men and women gathered together in the home of Christian Poock to form what would become St. Luke's. The next year, St. Lukes officially had its first pastor, Reverand F. A. Meusch. That year they also became a member of the German Evangelical Synod of North America. In 1955 the church offically joined the United Church of Christ. They continued to function and provide community and spirtiual outreach until it was decided that the church was no longer able to function. The final service was held in 2003, on the 95th anniversary of the opening. This collection contains church records and printed materials. Church records include baptism and confirmation, deaths and marriages, membership lists, anniversary material and obituaries. Printed material includes pamphlets, publications, photos and newspaper articles.
St. Luke's United Church of Christ (Dayton, Ohio)
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Collection was a gift by Mary Wood, daughter of Ellen Hix, former treasurer of St. Luke's in 2017; Accession 2017-07.
Historical Information
In 1908, a group of men and women gathered together in the home of Christian Poock to form what would become St. Luke's. The next year, St. Lukes officially had its first pastor, Reverand F. A. Meusch. That year they also became a member of the German Evangelical Synod of North America. In 1955 the church offically joined the United Church of Christ. They continued to function and provide community and spirtiual outreach until it was decided that the church was no longer able to function. The final service was held in 2003, on the 95th anniversary of the opening.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains church records and printed materials. Church records include baptism and confirmation, deaths and marriages, membership lists, anniversary material and obituaries. Printed material includes pamphlets, publications, photos and newspaper articles.
Arrangement
This collection arranged into two series and each individual series is arranged chronologically.
Series 1: Church Records, 1908-2013.
Series 2: Printed Material, 1911-2011.
Baptismal records.; Church finance.; Church membership.; Church records and registers.; Marriage records.; Necrologies.; Obituaries.; Dayton (Ohio) -- Church history.; St. Luke's United Church of Christ (Dayton, Ohio)
- Church records, 1908 2013; 1908-2013; 14 Folders
  Scope and Contents
  This series of church records include baptismal and confirmation records, necrologies, marriage records, membership lists, financial records, anniversary materials, and obituaries.
  - Baptism and confirmation records, 1908 2001; 1908-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Marriage and death records, 1909 2003; 1909-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pastors, 1941 1979; 1941-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership list, 1945 2003; 1945-1955, 2003; 1945 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Urban renewal, 1954 1961; 1954-1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - State of Ohio certificate, 1976 January 9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 90th anniversary, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Historical notes, 1998, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - St. Luke's 95th anniversary, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - St. Luke's UCC closing ceremony video, 2003 October 19 (Box 2, Cassette 1)
  - Treasurer's reports, 2003 2004; 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Obituaries, 2006 2013; 2006-2013 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - St. Luke's final luncheon, 2011 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Confirmation reunion names, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Constitution and by-laws, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Printed material, 1911 2011; 1911-2011; 10 Items
  This series of printed material includes pamphlets, publications, photos, and newspaper articles.
  - Publications, 1911 1927; 1911-1927 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Publications, 1937 1941; 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Anniversary pamphlets, 1938 1973; 1938-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Evangelical and Reformed News, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The St. Lukan, 1943 1948; 1943-1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - My First 50 Years in Dayton, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper articles, 1968 2011; 1968-2011 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anniversary pamphlets, 1978 1987; 1978-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - St. Luke's wooden art piece, 1987 (Box 3, Object 1)
  - St. Luke's Reunion Photos, 2007 (Box 2, Item 2)
  - Photos, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)